＜５年以下の懲役 または➡
50万円以下の
罰金に処せられます＞
＜後悔しても 元には戻せない＞
不正視聴!?
i realise the screaming pain
hearing loud in my brain
but i'm going straight ahead with the scar
I should just get over it and I should just stop feeling it
wasurete shimaeba ii yo kanjinaku nacchaeba ii
and so I covered my grazed heart
surimuita kokoro ni futa wo shitan da
I don't care if I'm hurt 'cause I don't feel pain anymore
kizutsuitatte heki da yo mou itami wa nai kara ne
all while you limped on while dragging your feet behind you
sono ashi wo hikizuri nagara mo
I had lost sight of myself
miushinatta jibun jishin ga
which had crumbled loudly to the ground
oto wo taete kuzureteita
but then I realised it was just the sound of the wind...
kizukeba kaze no oto dake ga
I came here to tell you something following my deep scars
tsutae ni kita yo kizuato wo tadotte
before I am completely crushed by this vast world
sekai ni oshitsubusarete shimau mae ni
do you remember that sky of tears
oboeteru kana namida no sora wo
that pain protected you for me
ano itami ga kimi no koto wo mamotte kureta
that pain is always protecting you
sono itami ga itsumo kimi wo mamotterunda
can you hear me so am i
The Light & Dark
of the Mangekyo Sharingan
((イタチ : 強くなったな。))
You've become... strong.
前とまったく同じセリフにカラス。
The same line as before...
and the bird...
お得意の幻術で茶番か？
Another farce with
your special genjutsu?
何が知りたい？
What do you want to know?
最後ではないが 聞いてやる。
It's not over,
but I'll hear you out.
もう一度言う。
I'll say it once more...
一族を皆殺しにしたあのタイミングで➡
When you killed off the entire clan,
アンタは もう１人の存在を口にした。
you mentioned the existence
of another person.
アンタが殺さなかった うちは。
So that Uchiha member you didn't kill
was a co-conspirator.
ソイツはつまり
協力者だったってことだ。
いくらアンタでも 警務部隊を
１人でやれるはずがない。
Even you could not kill
the entire Police Force alone.
ちゃんと気づいたか。
So you figured it out...
誰だ？
Who is it?!
うちはマダラだ。
It's Uchiha Madara...
((その瞳力と
わし以上にまがまがしいチャクラ。
With that vision and chakra
more ominous than my own...
かつての うちはマダラと同じだな。
It's just like... Uchiha Madara,
from long ago...
(知るかよ そんなヤツ))
Hell if I know... that person.
うちはマダラ？
Uchiha... Madara?!
木ノ葉隠れ創始者の１人。
One of the founders
of Hidden Leaf Village...
万華鏡写輪眼を
最初に開眼した男だ。
The man who first possessed
the Mangekyo Sharingan.
創始者？
Founder?
マダラなら
とっくに死んでいるはずだ。
That Madara
should be long dead!
オレをおちょくってんのか？
Are you making fun of me?!
マダラは生きている。
Madara is alive...
信じる信じないは お前次第だ。
It's up to you whether you believe
that or not.
戯れ言はやめろ！
Stop joking around!
人は 誰もが
己の知識や認識に頼り➡
In order to survive, we cling to
all we know and understand.
縛られ生きている。
それを現実という名で呼んでな。
And we label it reality.
しかし
知識や認識とは曖昧なものだ。
But knowledge and understanding
are ambiguous.
その現実は 幻かもしれない。
That reality could be an illusion.
人は皆
思い込みのなかで生きている。
All humans live with
the wrong assumptions.
そうは考えられないか？
Isn't that another way
of looking at it?
いったい何が言いたい？
Just what are you trying to say?
マダラが死んでいるというのは
お前の勝手な思い込みだ。
It's only your assumption
that Madara is dead.
かつてお前が オレを優しい兄だと
思い込んでいたようにな。
In exactly the same way
you once assumed that
I was your kind older brother.
お前が望むような兄を
演じ続けてきたのは➡
I just pretended to be the kind
of brother you wanted...
お前の器を確かめるためだ。
in order to measure your vessel.
あの夜の出来事…
幼かったオレには➡
What happened that night...
I was so young and thought
it was all an illusion.
幻にしか思えなかった。
ひどい幻術の中にいるのだと
そう思いたかった！
That I was caught in
a cruel genjutsu...
I wanted to believe that.
だが あれは…
まぎれもない現実だった！
But that was... unmistakably reality!
今のオレの眼は 昔とは違う！
My eye is not like it was
in the past!
オレの写輪眼は 幻術を見抜く！
My Sharingan can see
through genjutsu!
フッ…。 あいかわらず
強気な物言いだな。
You still speak with such confidence.
その言葉…
とりあえず 受け取っておこう。
But for now, I'll take your word for it.
小芝居につきあうのは
このへんでいいだろう。
Why don't we end this little charade?
強気はいいが…。
サスケ お前はまだ➡
Being confident is fine.
But Sasuke, your eye still isn't
the same as mine.
オレと同じ眼を
持ってはいないようだな。
((そして いつか
オレと同じ眼を持って➡
Then one day, come before me with
the same eye that I possess.
(オレの前に来い！))
お前の大事なものを
殺しきれなかったか。
So... you couldn't kill the friend
who is most dear to you.
そんな甘い思いで オレの前に
やってきたというのか？
And you dared to appear before me
with such weak resolve?
なら さっさと万華鏡写輪眼を
使って オレを殺ってみろ。
Then hurry it up and try to kill me
with your Mangekyo Sharingan!
それとも 今のオレでは
己の器を量りかねるか？
Or is it too difficult to test
your capability against me now?
はぁ…。
たいした自信だ。
You're pretty sure of yourself...
(白ゼツ)２人とも
さっきから全然 動かないね。
Neither of them has moved
for a while.
(黒ゼツ)
幻術を かけあっているだけだ。
They're just feeling each other out
with genjutsu.
万華鏡写輪眼… この眼は特別。
Mangekyo Sharingan...
This eye is special...
開眼したときから
その眼は 闇へと向かう。
From the moment it awakens,
it goes towards the dark.
使えば使うほど 封印されていく。
And the more it is used,
the more it is sealed.
どういうことだ？
What do you mean?
万華鏡は… いずれ 光を失う。
In time, the Mangekyo Sharingan
loses its light.
失明…。 それが 九尾を
コントロールする力を得る代償か。
Blindness...
Is that the trade-off for the power
to control the Nine-Tails?
フッ…。
オレの言ったとおり
集会場の石版を読んだようだな。
You did as I instructed and
read the lithograph in
the meeting room?
マダラ… いったい 何者だ。
Madara... Exactly who and what is he?
その眼で 九尾を手懐けた
最初の男。
The first one ever to use that eye
to tame the Nine-Tails.
オレの相棒であり 師であり
不滅の男。
An immortal man who is both
my partner and my mentor...
そして 万華鏡写輪眼の
もう１つの秘密を暴いた➡
And the only one to uncover
the other secret
of the Mangekyo Sharingan.
唯一の男。
それが うちはマダラだ。
That... is Uchiha Madara.
万華鏡写輪眼の
もう１つの秘密だと!?
The other secret of
Mangekyo Sharingan?
"Fox"
九尾を手懐ける瞳力…。
It has another ocular power aside
from taming the Nine-Tails?
それ以外にも
何かあるっていうのか!?
そうだ。 もう１つの秘密…。
Yes... One more secret.
The most important secret.
それが 最も重要な秘密だ。
重要な秘密？
Most important secret?
What is it?
なんだ!?
なんだ!? 答えろ！
What is it?! Answer me!
少し 昔話をしてやろう。
Let me tell you a little
about the past.
うちはの歴史にまつわる話だ。
It concerns the history
of the Uchiha.
かつて マダラにも兄弟がいた。
Long ago, Madara had a brother...
A younger brother.
弟だ。
(イタチ)うちはマダラと弟…。
Uchiha Madara and
his younger brother...
幼き頃より ２人は
互いの力を高めあい 競いあった。
From the time they were little,
they honed their skills and
competed with each other.
２人は写輪眼を開眼し 兄弟の名は
いつしか 一族の中でも➡
The Mangekyo Sharingan awakened
in them both...
and in time, they were considered
special by their clan.
特別なものになっていった。
２人は さらなる瞳力の成長を求め
競いあい…。
Both sought to sharpen
their ocular powers
and competed against each other.
兄弟は それぞれの大事な者たちを
手にかけ➡
And the brothers...
They killed off those important to them
ついに
万華鏡写輪眼を開眼したのだ。
and finally awakened
the Mangekyo Sharingan.
それは うちは一族
始まって以来のことだった。
It had never before been seen
among the Uchiha.
２人は その瞳力をもって
うちはを束ね➡
The brothers used their
ocular powers to take control
兄のマダラは リーダーとなった。
and Madara became the leader.
しかし 順調だった マダラの身に
ある異変が生じ始める。
However, a change began to
occur in Madara
who had been physically fine.
さっき 話したな。
この眼は特別だ と。
As I mentioned earlier,
this eye is special.
使えば使うほど 封印され
行き着く先は まったくの闇。
The more you use it,
the more it is sealed...
until you end up with total darkness.
これが 万華鏡写輪眼の末路だ。
That is the ultimate fate of
the Mangekyo Sharingan.
大きな瞳力… 力を得るかわりに
その力は 自ら閉じ 光を失う。
The price for gaining power is
destroying it yourself,
losing its light.
マダラは 光を取り戻すため
あらゆる手を尽くすが➡
In order to regain his sight,
Madara tried every means possible...
何一つ
効果を得られるものはなかった。
yet nothing worked.
絶望した。 そして 万華鏡に
とりつかれた マダラは 光を求め…。
He was in despair.
Madara became haunted by
the Mangekyo Sharingan and sought light.
((マダラ : 許せ))
Forgive me...
(イタチ)自ら 弟の両眼を
奪い取ったのだ。
He took both eyes from
his younger brother.
マダラは 新たな光を手に入れた。
Madara now possessed new light.
そして もう二度と その眼の光は
閉じることがなかった。
And... never again did the light fade
from his eyes.
永遠の万華鏡写輪眼。
An eternal Mangekyo Sharingan!
弟の眼は新しい宿主を得ることで
永遠の光を手に入れたという。
It is said that his younger brother's eyes
gained eternal light
when it found a new host...
そればかりか 変化を起こした。
特有の新しい瞳術が
その眼に生まれたのだ。
And it triggered a change.
A new, unique ocular jutsu was born
in those eyes.
ただし 瞳のやりとりは
一族間でしか行えない。
However, the exchange of eyes
can only be conducted
この方法で 誰もが 新しい力を
手にできるわけではない。
among clan members.
Furthermore, not everyone can attain
new powers from this method.
これは その後 多くの犠牲の上に
築かれた 歴史上の事実。
That is the historical fact that remains
after countless were sacrificed.
それが この眼の
もう１つの秘密だ。
That is the other secret of this eye...
マダラは その力を使い
あらゆる忍一族を➡
Madara used his power and took control
of one ninja clan after another.
次々に束ねていった。
そして 忍最強と謳われていた
森の千手一族と手を組み➡
Ultimately, he formed an alliance with
the Senju Clan of the Forest,
新たな組織を設立したのだ。
which was touted as
the strongest ninja clan
and established a new organization.
その後 マダラは 千手のリーダーであった
後の初代火影と➡
Later, he clashed with the leader
of the Senju Clan,
里の方針を巡って 対立。
the future First Hokage,
over the course the village would take.
主導権争いに敗れはしたが
マダラは今も その瞳力とともに➡
He lost the battle over leadership,
but Madara still lives with
his ocular powers intact.
あり続けている。
新たに 暁を組織し
その陰に 姿を隠してな。
He formed a new organization
called the Akatsuki
and hides himself in its shadows.
16年前
九尾が 木ノ葉を襲った事件は➡
Sixteen years ago,
マダラが起こしたものだ。
Madara instigated the Nine-Tails' attack
on Hidden Leaf Village.
だが それも
四代目に阻止されてしまった。
But that too was foiled by
the Fourth Hokage.
つまり…。
In short...
今のマダラは 負け犬だ。
Madara is a bitter, defeated loser...
うちはの本当の高みを
手にするのは ヤツじゃない。
He is not worthy of becoming
the best among the Uchiha.
あの男… マダラを超え➡
I am the one...
本当の高みへと近づくのは
このオレだ。
who shall surpass Madara and
become the ultimate ninja!
そして今 オレは マダラを超える力を
ようやく 手にできる！
And now! I can finally obtain power
that exceeds Madara's!
サスケ！
お前は オレにとっての新たな光だ！
Sasuke! You are my new light!
お前は オレのスペアだ！
You have my spare eyes!
元来 うちは一族は
万華鏡写輪眼のために➡
Originally, the Uchiha Clan
killed off friends
友と殺し合い
永遠の瞳力を得るために➡
in order to possess
Mangekyo Sharingan.
親兄弟で殺し合い
そうして力を誇示し続けてきた➡
Parents and siblings killed each other off
to possess eternal ocular powers...
汚れた一族なのだ！
And they showed off this power...
They are a tainted clan!
その一族の中に
生まれ落ちたときから➡
And, from the day you were born,
お前も この血塗られた運命に
巻き込まれている！
you have been inevitably linked
to this blood-sullied fate!
さあ こい！ 弟よ！
Now come! My younger brother!
オレは お前を殺して
一族の宿命から解放され➡
I shall kill you...
and free myself from this fate
本当の変化を手にする！
and bring about true change!
制約を抜け
己の器から己を解き放つ！
I will be free of the constraints
that bind me!
((ただ お前とオレは
唯一無二の兄弟だ。
But, we only have each other
as siblings.
お前の越えるべき壁として➡
(オレは お前とともにあり続けるさ))
I'm always going to be there for you,
even if it's only as an obstacle
for you to overcome.
オレたちは 互いのスペアだ！
We are each other's spares!
((お前は オレをうとましく思い
憎んでいた。
You've been jealous of me
and resented me.
このオレを超えることを
望み続けていた。
You've harbored hopes
of surpassing me.
(だからこそ生かしてやる。
オレのために))
That is why I am allowing you to live.
(イタチ)それこそが
うちは兄弟の絆なのだ！
For my sake...
This is the true bond between
the brothers of the Uchiha!
《どうやら 心の中のオレが
ちゃんと見えたようだな》
It seems... you are finally seeing
what's inside my heart.
すべては このためか…。
So it was all for this...
((名は うちはサスケ。
嫌いなものなら たくさんあるが➡
My name is Sasuke Uchiha.
好きなものは 別にない。
There are lots of things I hate.
And not many things I like.
それから 夢なんて言葉で
終わらす気はないが 野望はある。
Also... I have no intention
of saying I have a dream.
一族の復興と➡
But I do have ambition!
(ある男を必ず… 殺すことだ))
To restore my clan... and kill...
a certain man.
やっと… 辿り着いた。
I've finally arrived...
目的を果たすときがきた！
The moment to fulfill my goal!
お前には オレの死にざまが
見えているらしいな。
You say you can see my death...
万華鏡写輪眼を持つオレに
勝てはしない。
But you cannot win against
my Mangekyo Sharingan.
お前の目的は
残念だが幻に終わる。
Unfortunately, your goal will end
as an illusion.
なぜなら お前は
万華鏡を持ってはいない。
Because you do not possess
the Mangekyo Sharingan.
((お前は弱い。 なぜ弱いか…。
You're still weak...
(足りないからだ。 憎しみが…))
You're weak,
because you don't have enough hate.
アンタが その眼をいくら使おうが➡
You can use your eyes all you like,
このオレの憎しみで
幻は 現実になる。
but my hate will turn
my illusion into reality!
アンタの現実は… 死だ。
Your reality...
is death!
《撃ち合いのなかで
影分身の印まで！》
Even during our shoot out,
he was able to weave signs
for a Shadow Clone!
千鳥を！
You ran it through with Chidori?!
ぐっ！
ぐっ… うっ…。
うっ!? ゲホッ ゲホッ ゲホッ！
許せ サスケ…。
Forgive me, Sasuke...
これが オレの現実だ。
光をもらう。
This is my reality...
Give me your light.
ぐあぁ～!!
you are next to me
omae ga tonari ni iru
you are laughing
omae ga waratte iru
you seem so happy
omae ga ureshisou de
so I laughed too
ore mo waratta
you were so innocent and naive
omae wa mujaki datta
you were so kindhearted
omae wa yasashi katta
you sometimes cried
omae wa tokidoki naki
so I was troubled
ore wa komatta
who did I ask strength from at that time
dare yori tsuyosa wo motometa ano koro
since that was my one and only weakness
ore no tatta hitotsu no yowasa ga
that was you
omae datta
and it was you
omae datta n da
I want to see you
aitai
overnights
yoru wo koete
over time
toki wo koete
I want to see you now
ima aitai
Next Episode
That ended quicker than I expected...
《ヤマト : そうそう ナルトは
寝相が悪いから離れて寝なきゃ》
Itachi's won.
Sasuke can no longer move...
なに!?
All that remains is for Itachi
to finish him off.
誰だ!?
Do you really think so?
(キバ)赤丸だって
ちゃんと踊れるんだ…。
Of course.
There's no way a Sharingan could win
against the Mangekyo Sharingan.
今度は キミか…。
(キバ)通牙！
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Amaterasu!"
寝ぼけてるのに なんという威力。
サクラちゃんのカタキだよ！
Guess we can't take our eyes away
from this one.
Amaterasu
うぅ… この声は！
That's right.
サクラちゃん…
やっぱり男だったんだ。
Naruto tosses around when he sleeps,
so I'd better move away.
What?!
ん？
通牙！
Who's there?!
螺旋丸！
うわっ!? うわぁ～！
Akamaru can dance just as well too...
Now it's you...
まったく
どんな寝相してるんだよ…。
Tunneling Fang!
(シノ)同感だ。
えっ？
He's half-asleep... but what power...
(シノ)いいかげん
おとなしく寝てもらおうか。
I'm avenging Sakura-chan!
ぎょっ!? ギャー!! ってばよ！
Uhh... This voice... isn't...?
Sakura-chan... You're a man, after all...
(ラハール)アクノロギア…。
ゼレフが本当に… そう言ったのか？
Tunneling Fang!
Rasengan!
(ドランバルト)すまねえ…
動くことすらできなかった。
そんなことはいい。
本当に ゼレフが 「アクノロギア」と…。
Cripes, talk about tossing and turning...
I agree.
Huh?
Can you lie still and go to sleep?!
て… 撤退！ 全部隊 撤退！
No!
天狼島の調査を
これにて すべて打ち切る！